Guide to the Richard Cardarelli Papers 1969-2005 GLBTQ 2012.09 GLBTQ.2012.09
Connecticut Polish American Archives
Richard Cardarelli Papers
1969-2005
GLBTQ.2012.09
Connecticut Polish American Archives
26.0 Linear feet
Richard Cardarelli was a celebate gay activist priest living and working in the Hartford Area for most of his career. He co-founded Dignity/Hartford and celebrated mass with the organization. His papers include subject files which he kept for research and reference, as well as several documents pertaining to Dignity/Hartford and other Dignity organizations around the country. Scrapbooks of photos from various events in which he was involved form a good portion of the collection.
Cardarelli, Richard
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical note
Richard Cardarelli (August 25, 1951 – June 22, 2012) was a gay activist, an ordained Catholic priest and Franciscan Friar. His activism as a gay celebate priest eventually brought him to be excommunicated by the Catholic Church. A native of Connecticut, Cardarelli received his BA in French Literature from St. Michaels College in Vermont. After receiving a teaching certificate from Central Connecticut State College, he began teaching French and Religion at Xavier High School in Middletown, Connecticut. He entered the Capuchin Franciscan Order in 1976. He professed solemn vows in 1981 and was ordained a priest in 1982. He received his Masters of Divinity and a Masters of Theology at the Maryknoll School of Theology and served as chaplain to Mercy High School in Middletown, CT, and later as Director of his province's Office of Peace and Justice. His career as a gay activist began in 1971, the summer of his first gay parade in New York City. He later joined DIGNITY, USA, helping to found the Springfield/Hartford Chapter in 1975. This career paralleled his peace activities which started with his first peace march in Boston in 1969. Once he was assigned to full-time peace and justice activities, he engaged in civil disobedience to protest war, the nuclear arms race, apartheid in South Africa, and homophobia/heterosexism. His arrest at the Supreme Court for gay/lesbian rights made news headlines and his public gay ministry began to be questioned by the church hierarchy. With the support of his superior, he was very public with gay activism and ministry, first and foremost with DIGNITY and then with the Connecticut Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights. He engaged in dialogue with local bishops and testified at the State Capitol for gay legislation. He spoke at colleges, on panels for clergy and religious, on television and radio, and continued to march each June in New York City. After DIGNITY was forced out of Catholic facilities around the country, he came out as a gay celibate priest in the press. His priestly faculties were revoked. After he stood with ILGO in New York City when it was barred from the St. Patrick's Day parade, he was forced into a leave of absence from his Order and active ministry. After a few years, he was told that he would never be able to function as a priest again. Devastated, but still committed to gay ministry, he sought creative ways by which he could continue his ministry. He discovered the Independent Catholic Movement and made inquiries into one such denomination. He started a parish for this church, but realized that he would sacrifice his priesthood. However, his new superior told him that his celebrating Mass for this new Church caused his automatic excommunication from the Church and expulsion from the Order. Cut off from his religious family and beloved Church, he later joined the Ecumenical Catholic Church. Within a relatively short time of rapid growth, the ECC appointed him as bishop of the new diocese of New England. Unfortunately, this community broke with the ECC in its attempts to be less patriarchal and more egalitarian and ecumenical, without loss of Catholic identity. The American Apostolic Catholic Church was born from this experience, embracing lay and ordained persons who share authority; women and men are ordained; all persons are offered the seven sacraments. However, this denomination was not able to satisfy Richard's longing to be a part of the Church Universal in living out his baptismal commitment and his dedication to social justice for the g/l/b/t community. Thus, in May 2000, he was welcomed into the Episcopal Church and into membership within the Anglo-Catholic Parish of Grace Church in Hartford. He continued to participate in gay causes and in Dignity/USA until his death.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged alphabetically by the subject title of the folder. Series I includes Richard Carderelli's personal correspondence files, writings, and files he kept on various topics, especially Dignity, which comprises two large boxes of folders. Series II is comprised of photographs and scrapbooks. Series III is comprised of videotapes and one audio cassette. Series IV is comprised of a Lectionary and Sacramentary from Dignity/Hartford, and other realia, including T-Shirts from various events and organizations.
Scope and Content
The Richard Cardarelli Papers contain primarily his own personal research and reference files. These include files pertaining to Dignity/Hartford for the period 1975 to 2003. The bulk of the collection are subject files kept by Cardarelli, and several scrapbooks of photos pertaining to events in which he was involved. Interspersed within the files are his own correspondence and writings. The realia includes T-shirts, a lectionary and sacramentary from Dignity/Hartford, and various momentos from Richard Cardarelli's religious activities, activism and conferences.
Oral history interview
An oral history interview of Richard Cardarelli is available within the Digital Collections of the GLTBQ Archives on the website of the Elihu Burritt Library.
Cardarelli, Richard; Christian gays; Clergy -- Connecticut; connecticut womens rights; Dignity/Hartford; Dignity/USA; Gay clergy; Gay community -- Connecticut; Gay pride parades; Gay rights -- United States -- History; Gays -- Connecticut -- Exhibitions; Homosexuality--Religious aspects--Catholic Church; Radical Faeries (New Age movement)
- Series I: Subject Files
  - Act Up [flyers, articles], 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Affirming Every Person - New England Conference About Lesbians & Gay Men, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AIDS [flyers, brochures, articles], 1983-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AIDS Material, 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Always Our Children - A pastoral message to parents of homosexual children, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Apostolic Catholic Church, Connecticut, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anglican Church of St. Savior, San Francisco, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anglican Communion and Homosexuality, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anglican Communion and Homosexuality (1 of 2), 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anglican Communion and Homosexuality (2 of 2), 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anglican Communion and Homosexuality, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Articles [newspaper and magazine articles on homosexuality, legislation and movies. Articles about gays and organized religion especially the Catholic Church], 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bayside, The Lourdes of America Articles, with protest correspondence to Editor of Hartford Courant., 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies - Homosexuality and Catholicism, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boswell, John, Rediscovering Gay History [pamphlet], 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bridge Building Award, presented to Sister Margaret Farley [program], Nov. 16, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Keith, Annals of Gay Spirit Radio [typescript, 162 leaves], 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Communications Ministry, Inc. Convention booklet and correspondence related to newsletter, August 31, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Call to Action [conference announcements], Nov 5-7, 1999; Nov. 7-9, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Call to Compassion: The Seven Last Words of Christ [typescript], undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cardarelli, Richard [articles about], 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cardarelli, Richard [correspondence], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Carderelli, Richard, [correspondence regarding archives at CCSU], 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Carderelli, Richard, [correspondence], 1990-2001 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cardarelli, Richard, The Faithful Faerie, [manuscript] Typescript, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cardarelli, Richard, Farewell Party for Fr. Richard, Pond House, April 11, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cardarelli, Richard, obituary and news articles, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cathedral Project, Hartford (speech, both handwritten and typed copies), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cathedral Project, New York [protests against Cardinal John J. O'Connor], 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Catholic Church and Homosexuality (printed articles from various web sources), 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Catholic Coalition for Gay Civil Rights, 1987-1992 (Box 2)
  - Catholics For A Free Choice, Campaign to end ban on condoms (copies of web sources), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Celibate and Gay [writings by Brother William Roberts] (1 of 2), 1976-1999 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Celibate and Gay [writings by Brother William Roberts] (2 of 2), 1976-1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Children from the Shadows [conference materials], 1994, 1997 & 1998 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Children from the Shadows [conference materials], 1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Children from the Shadows [conference materials], 2001 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Children from the Shadows [conference materials], 2002 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee, flyers, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Church documents (on homosexuality), undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Church of St. Savior (celebration of 3rd anniversary mass program), undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Church of the Advent of Christ the King, San Francisco, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Civil Disobedience At The U. S. Supreme Court [March on Washington material], October 13, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Collazo, Vincent, Jonathan Lebolt Wedding Invitation and Thank you pamphlet, April 10,1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Committee for Women's Concerns, 1999 - (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Communication Retreat, August, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Congregation for The Doctrine of the Faith: Considerations Catholic Response to Legislative proposals on the Non-Discrimination of Homosexual Persons, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - CT Coalition for Lesbian and Gay Civil Rights, Middlesex County Chapter, [flyers minutes of meetings, articles], 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - CT Lesbian and Gay Antiviolence Project, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Connecticut Pride Day official programs, 1985, 1986, 1988, 1992, 1994, 1996, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Connecticut Stonewall Congress Programs, 1997, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Courage (Support Group), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Defenders USA, San Francisco (informational brochures and web printouts), undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Different Voices, One Community Conference, New London, February 20, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Dignity and the Inquisition Follies [Hartford Dignity typescript], undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dignity, [Articles about and by], 1986-1989, 1999, 2000-Present (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dignity Atlanta, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dignity Boston, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dignity Convention, Boston, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dignity Convention, Boston, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dignity Convention, Denver 1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dignity Convention, New York, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dignity Convention, Seattle, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dignity Convention, Bal Harbour, FL, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dignity Convention, San Francisco, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dignity Convention, Washington, DC, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dignity Convention, New Orleans, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Dignity Convention, Los Angeles, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dignity Convention Washington D.C. 2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Dignity Convention, Chicago, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Dignity Convention, Las Vegas, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dignity Convention, Philadelphia, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Dignity Convention Austin, TX 2007 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dignity Convention, Austin, TX (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dignity Convention, San Francisco, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Dignity East Coast Conference, Philadelphia, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dignity Fall River Retreat, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dignity Hartford 1979 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Dignity Hartford 1980 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Dignity Hartford 1981 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Dignity Hartford 1982 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Dignity Hartford 1983 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dignity Hartford 1984 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Dignity Hartford 1985 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Dignity Hartford 1986 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Dignity Hartford 1987 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dignity Hartford 1988 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dignity Hartford 1989 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dignity Hartford 1990 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dignity Hartford 1991 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dignity Hartford 1992 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dignity Hartford 1993 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dignity Hartford 1994 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dignity Hartford 1995 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Dignity Hartford 1996 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dignity Hartford 1997 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dignity Hartford 1998 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dignity Hartford 1999 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dignity Hartford 2000 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Dignity Hartford 2001 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Dignity Hartford 2002 [flyers, notes, booklets] (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Dignity Hartford 2002 [flyers, notes, booklets] (2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Dignity Hartford 2002 [flyers, notes, booklets] (3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Dignity Hartford 2003 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Dignity Hartford 2004 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Dignity Hartford 2005 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dignity Hartford 2006 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Dignity Hartford 2007 Final Mass and Ceremonies (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Dignity Hartford Archbishop's Committee, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Dignity Hartford Archdiocese of Hartford, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Dignity Hartford Board 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Dignity Hartford Board 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Dignity Hartford Board 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Dignity Hartford Board 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dignity Hartford Commemorative Booklet, by Richard Cardarelli, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dignity Hartford Fifteenth Anniversary, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Dignity Hartford History [typescript], 1990-2003 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Dignity Hartford History [typescript], 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Dignity Hartford Liturgy Committee, 1983-1990 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Dignity Hartford Public Expression of Hurt, [flyers, minutes, notes, protesting the Archbishop's expulsion of Dignity], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Dignity Hartford Survey, 1994, March, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Dignity Hartford Contacts Lists -- New England, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Dignity Hartford Tenth Anniversary, [Program], 1985 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Dignity Hartford Liturgies (Black Binder), undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Dignity International [flyers, notes, booklets], 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dignity Jacksonville, FL [flyers, notes, booklets], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dignity Los Angeles [flyers, notes, booklets], undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dignity National [flyers, notes, booklets], 1987 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Dignity New Haven [flyers, notes, booklets], undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dignity New York, [flyers, pamphlets], 1977-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Dignity Providence Retreat [flyers, notes, booklets], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dignity Region I Convention [flyers, notes, booklets], 1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dignity Region I Liturgy Workshop [flyers, notes, booklets], October 22, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Dignity Region I Retreat [flyers, notes, booklets], 1982 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Dignity Regional Conference, Buffalo [flyers, notes, booklets], May 24-26, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Dignity Retreat 1984 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dignity Retreat 1985 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dignity Retreat 1986 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Dignity Retreat 1987 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Dignity Retreat 1993 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dignity Retreat 2002 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dignity Region I Retreat 1989 [flyers, notes, booklets] (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dignity Regional Convention, Boston Dignity Retreat 1987 [flyers, notes, booklets], February 25-27, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Dignity San Diego [newsletters, correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Dignity San Francisco [flyers, notes, booklets], 2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Dignity San Francisco [flyers, notes, booklets], 2004 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Dignity San Francisco [flyers, notes, booklets], 2005 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Dignity San Francisco [flyers, notes, booklets], 2006-2008 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dignity San Francisco [flyers, notes, booklets] (1 of 2), 2007 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Dignity San Francisco [flyers, notes, booklets] (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Dignity Springfield, [flyers, articles, notes], 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dignity Springfield, [flyers, articles, notes], 1976 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Dignity Springfield [flyers, articles, notes], 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Dignity Springfield/Hartford, [charter, treasurer report, etc.], 1977 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Dignity Springfield/Hartford, [charter, treasurer report, etc.], 1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Dignity Suffolk, New York, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Dignity/USA [articles, flyers], 1988-1991, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Dignity/USA [articles, flyers], 2004 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Dignity/USA [articles, flyers], 2005 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Dignity/USA [articles, flyers], 2006 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Dignity/USA Restructuring Task Force, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Dignity/USA Worship Committee, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Dignity/Washington, [flyers, brochures], 2000 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Dignity-Integrity Newsletter Rochester, New York, June, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Diocesan Programs for Gays and Lesbians, [articles], 1981-1985, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Episcopal Church and Homosexuality, [articles], 2003 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Episcopal Church of St. John the Evangelist, San Francisco, 2003-2005 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Episcopal Diocese of California. Celebration and Blessing of a Covenant Relationship [various drafts], 1983-2004 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Father Bernard Lynch, [articles], 1989 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Freedom in Christ Evangelical Church, San Francisco [brochure], undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Gallup Poll of Catholic Opinion, [Questionnaire], 1992 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Gay and Lesbian Youth Workbook Dignity Convention, New York, August, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Gay Canon of the Mass, by R. Cardarelli, [typescript], undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Gay Catholic Articles, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Gay Catholic Articles, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Gay Hollywood, 2000, A Special Report. Entertainment, Oct. 6, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Gay Marriage [news articles and newsletter], 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Gay Marriage [album of articles] 1 of 3, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gay Marriage [album of articles] 2 of 3, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gay Marriage [album of articles] 3 of 3, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Gay Marriage [album of articles] 1 of 2, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gay Marriage [album of articles] 2 of 2, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gay Men's Health Summit, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gay Parents & Parents of Gays, [articles], 1976-1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Gay Religious Archives 1 of 2, 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Gay Religious Archives 2 of 2, 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gay Rights Articles, 1975-1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gay Rights Bill, Connecticut, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Gay Seminarians 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Gay Spirit Camp. Easton Mountain, [brochure], 2003 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Gay Youth, [articles, flyers, NGTF student organization packets], 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Gunnison, Foster Memorial Service, February 19, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Hate Crime Statistics 1995, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Homophobia...responses in our faith communities, April 9, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Holy Unions [sermons, liturgy, flyers], 1982-1989 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Homosexuality and Churches, [articles], 2004 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Horizon Foundation, San Francisco, [letter, flyer], 2000 (Box 6, Folder 20)